Guide to the Investigation Files of the Rapp-Coudert Committee TAM.533
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Microfilm Reel List (with Cross-Reference to Original Box and Folder Locations), 1919-1953
  - McAvoy, Clifford (Deputy Commissioner, Dept. of Public Welfare, Chair of Anti-Committee Public Meeting), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0438, Box-folder 5-RC219)
  - McDonald, Milo F. (Principal of Bushwick High School, Editor of The Educational Signpost, published by American Education Association): Includes Correspondence, The Educational Signpost (1938-1941) and ASU Flyers (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0453, Box-folder 5-RC220)
  - Lists (German American Bund): Includes Witnesses-Private Hearings before Committee, Teachers Who Have Signed CP Nominating Petitions, Those Mentioned as Communists by Canning, Shermer, Grebanier, People Identified as Communist Party Members Who Have Testified... Have Not Testified, 1941-1942, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0580, Box-folder 5-RC221)
  - May Day Pictures (Photos of Parades), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0617, Box-folder 5-RC222)
  - Sampson-McDonald Material: Includes Milo McDonald Correspondence, Publications, American Education Association Minutes and Other Related Material, 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0001, Box-folder 5-RC223)
  - May Day Photostats, May Day: Includes The Daily Worker and New Theater School Class List, 1932-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0253, Box-folder 5-RC224)
  - May Day: Includes Parade Flyers, Articles and Notes, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0303, Box-folder 6-RC225)
  - May Day Parade Permits (applications), Police Report and The Daily Worker Article, 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0418, Box-folder 6-RC226)
  - May Day Photostats (from The Daily Worker), 1936-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0492, Box-folder 6-RC227)
  - May Day Photostats (from The Daily Worker and other publications), 1933-1935 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0510, Box-folder 6-RC228)
  - May Day Photostats (from The Daily Worker and The New York Times), 1920-1929 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0533, Box-folder 6-RC229)
  - Markoff, Abraham (Executive Committee of the Workers School), 1933-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0555, Box-folder 6-RC230)
  - Martin, William G.(Senator): Petition and Letter Concerning Bill Introduced in State Legislature to Ban American Student Union, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0575, Box-folder 6-RC231)
  - Mason, Albert C. (Substitute Teacher, Haaren Aviation Annex, Manhattan, 1930s), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0631, Box-folder 6-RC232)
  - Memos (primarily re: Italian Fascists), 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0637, Box-folder 6-RC233)
  - Meyer, Martin (Professor, Chemistry Department, Brooklyn College), 1940-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0697, Box-folder 6-RC234)
  - Metz, Julius (Seward Park High School, member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun, 1937), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0713, Box-folder 6-RC235)
  - Mueller, Otto (CCNY, Department of Romance Languages, French), 1939-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0717, Box-folder 6-RC236)
  - Marder, Lou: Hearing, Progressive Student Party, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0735, Box-folder 6-RC237)
  - Meeropole Exhibits (contains committee resolutions allowing release of private hearing test, minutes; Lewis Allen score, Strange Fruit, 1940), 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0743, Box-folder 6-RC238)
  - Murphy, Timothy (Principal, Samuel Gompers Vocational High School, Bronx; Chairman of Academic Department, Librarian, Administrator National Youth Administration): Includes Correspondence, Memoranda, Various Statements, Murphy's Response to Accusations, Articles and Report on American Educational Association, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 14-0767, Box-folder 6-RC239,1)
  - Murphy, Timothy (Principal, Samuel Gompers Vocational High School, Bronx; Chairman of Academic Department, Librarian, Administrator National Youth Administration): Includes Hearing Transcript, Correspondence, Brith Abraham Complaint and Report, Statements of Students and Teachers, Notes and Memoranda, 1919-1920, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0001, Box-folder 6-RC239,2)
  - Miller, William, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0373, Box-folder 6-RC240)
  - Mins, Leonard, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0378, Box-folder 6-RC241)
  - Miner, Louie M. (Miss), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0385, Box-folder 6-RC242)
  - Margolis, Samuel (CCNY-Library Staff Uptown), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0392, Box-folder 6-RC243)
  - Mintus, Jesse (CCNY - Clerk Recorders Office; active in Irish Republican causes; member of Committee and Legislative Conference of the City College which submitted a Tenure Bill draft in 1939; member of the Executive Council, the Caucus for Democratic Control), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0401, Box-folder 6-RC244)
  - Morais, Herbert M. (Assistant Professor History Dept. Brooklyn, suspended June 11, 1941; contributed to Science and Society in 1940), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0427, Box-folder 6-RC245)
  - Martin, Earl A. (Biology, Brooklyn College): Interview Summary, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0441, Box-folder 6-RC246)
  - Maslow, Abraham H., undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0447, Box-folder 6-RC247)
  - Monroe, Elizabeth N., undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0451, Box-folder 6-RC248)
  - Mozzeson, Henry (Young Communist League), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0455, Box-folder 6-RC249)
  - Motz, Lloyd (CCNY, Physics), 1935, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0459, Box-folder 6-RC250)
  - Miller, Helen (US Bureau of Labor Statistics): Decision and Order of Removal, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0474, Box-folder 6-RC251)
  - Nagel, Ernest, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0496, Box-folder 6-RC252)
  - Nathan, David S. (Math Department, CCNY), 1939-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0499, Box-folder 6-RC253)
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties: Pamphlet, Jul 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0523, Box-folder 6-RC254)
  - National Student League, 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0529, Box-folder 6-RC255)
  - Neff, Walter Scott (CCNY, Psychology Department): Includes Trial Committee Reports, Publications (e.g. College Newsletter, Teacher Worker), 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0541, Box-folder 6-RC256)
  - The New Masses (staff teaching at Workers School): Transcript, Sep 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0605, Box-folder 6-RC257)
  - Nunan, Peter (Teacher, PS 54, Harlem), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0609, Box-folder 6-RC258)
  - New Utrecht High School, Brooklyn (American Student Union): Includes Correspondence, Reports, Flyers, Publications, Hearing Summary, 1933-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0624, Box-folder 6-RC259)
  - New York Vocational High School for Boys PS 100, Manhattan (Sidney Lake, Principal): Correspondence, 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0840, Box-folder 6-RC260)
  - Olesen, Frederik A. (Hygiene, Assistant Professor, Brooklyn College): Conference with Olesen, Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0847, Box-folder 6-RC261)
  - Ogur, Maurice (Tutor, Chemistry, Brooklyn), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0850, Box-folder 6-RC262)
  - O'Neil's Protest Against Rapp-Coudert Interim Report (James O'Neil, Chairman, Dept. of Speech and Chair of Committee Appointed by President Gideonse to Study Committee's Interim Report of Dec 1, 1941): Text of O'Neil Report, Correspondence, 1941, 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0863, Box-folder 6-RC263)
  - Olsen, William (NYU, Member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election Isidore Begun, 1937): Flyer, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0889, Box-folder 6-RC264)
  - Passports: Includes "World Tourist" Files (List of those who obtained passports "charged to William Slake & George Primoff when they were Financial Secretaries of CP United States of America"), Photostats of Passports, 1928-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0893, Box-folder 6-RC265)
  - Parodneck, Clara: Private Hearing Exhibit (regarding Murphy Investigation, RC239), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0974, Box-folder 6-RC266)
  - Party Organizer: Photocopies of Various Articles, 1935-1936 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0978, Box-folder 6-RC267)
  - Paskoff, Benjamin (CCNY, Tutor in History): Includes Details of Anti-Committee Talk (Memorandum), Correspondence, Interview Summaries, Photograph, Publications, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-0989, Box-folder 6-RC268)
  - Paul, Martin A. (Chemistry), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-1030, Box-folder 6-RC269)
  - Peach, Harry (Physics Instructor, Brooklyn College), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-1034, Box-folder 6-RC270)
  - Penato-Galvan, Amelio (CCNY, French), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-1037, Box-folder 6-RC271)
  - Pollack, Sylvan A., 1930 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 15-1040, Box-folder 6-RC272)
  - Politis, Stephen (CCNY Student, ASU Member), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0001, Box-folder 6-RC273)
  - Pomerance, Isidor (Brooklyn College), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0056, Box-folder 6-RC274)
  - Progressive Education Association: The New York Teacher, Feb 1938 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0060, Box-folder 6-RC275)
  - Protests Against Rapp-Coudert Committee by Various Organizations: Telegrams and Letters of Opposition to Subpoenaing Teachers Union Membership Lists (includes ACLU), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0065, Box-folder 6-RC276)
  - The Protestant (also articles from The New York Herald Tribune and The Catholic News), 1942, 1943, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0338, Box-folder 6-RC277)
  - Queens College: Includes Material Concerning Professor William Withers and Professor Whitaker, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0353, Box-folder 6-RC278)
  - Public School 10 (Astoria, Queens): Vandalism (Swastika, American Flag): Includes Interviews, Correspondence and other Related Material, 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0376, Box-folder 6-RC279)
  - Queens College: Includes Notes of Interview with President Paul Klappen and Dean Margaret Kiely, 1942-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0441, Box-folder 6-RC280)
  - Receipts (of Exhibits): Includes Receipt of Application by Robert Kennedy to Quash a Subpoena along with Other Receipts, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0479, Box-folder 6-RC281)
  - Reiss, Marvin: Private Hearing Exhibit, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0602, Box-folder 6-RC282)
  - Riesel, Victor (Newspaper Columnist), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0606, Box-folder 6-RC283)
  - Riess, Bernard (Hunter College, Assistant Professor of Psychology and Secretary, College Teachers Union): Includes Outline of Testimony Centering on Role of Union, 1941-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0611, Box-folder 6-RC284)
  - Rosenthal, Max (Biology Instuctor and Director of CCNY House Plan), Mar 1941-Apr 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0648, Box-folder 6-RC285)
  - Roberts, Donald (Secretary of Alumni Association, Brooklyn), Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0660, Box-folder 6-RC286)
  - Robinson, Thomas (Private Exhibits, including The New York Student), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0664, Box-folder 6-RC287)
  - Roth, Harold H. (Tutor, CCNY English): Interview Notes, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0708, Box-folder 6-RC288)
  - Romanelli, Pasquale (Brooklyn College, Philosophy): Interview Notes, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0717, Box-folder 6-RC289)
  - Rosen, Edward (CCNY Instructor in History): Interview with Dr. Brandt (CCNY History Department), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0723, Box-folder 6-RC290)
  - Rabinowitz, Isaac (Director B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation): Interview, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0727, Box-folder 6-RC291)
  - Rabinow, Hannah, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0730, Box-folder 6-RC292)
  - Roach, Madonna, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0734, Box-folder 6-RC293)
  - Reiss, Marvin, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0738, Box-folder 6-RC294)
  - Rosenthal, Robert (CCNY Department of Chemistry), 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0741, Box-folder 6-RC295)
  - Rudman, Harry (English Instructor), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0760, Box-folder 6-RC296)
  - Roberts, Leslie Evans: Meeting Minutes - Committee for the Defense of Public Education, Mar 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0763, Box-folder 6-RC297)
  - Rogalin Exhibits: Contains Telegrams Regarding New Utrecht High School Peace Assembly, Apr 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0777, Box-folder 6-RC298)
  - Spiro, Mrs. Abraham: Phone Call Memorandum, Jul 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0783, Box-folder 6-RC299)
  - Shaw, Irwin: Letter Protesting Arrests of Brooklyn College Alumni Alan Shaw Lifshutz and Eli Jaffe, Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0786, Box-folder 7-RC300)
  - Souther, Sylvia Gross (Tutor-Speech, Brooklyn College) re: Denial of Reappointment, Jun 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0789, Box-folder 7-RC301)
  - Stuart, Meriweather (Classical Languages, Hunter College): Photographs, Private Hearing, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0794, Box-folder 7-RC302)
  - Stone, Adolph (High School of Music and Art): Correspondence, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0875, Box-folder 7-RC303)
  - Sherman, Annette (Mrs. Jack Gottseger, CCNY, Economics): Includes Digest of Private Testimony and List of Names and Activities of Faculty and Staff (CCNY), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0883, Box-folder 7-RC304)
  - Sampson's Data: Includes Investigator's Reports on Meetings of the Teachers and Profesional Committee for Thomas and Krueger and Jewish Teachers Association, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0940, Box-folder 7-RC305)
  - Shukatoff, Arnold (English Department, CCNY), 1935, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0959, Box-folder 7-RC306)
  - Small, Henry (CCNY), 1937 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0968, Box-folder 7-RC307)
  - Photostats of Articles from Publications such as New Masses, Young Communist Review, Progressive Weekly, 1934-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-0973, Box-folder 7-RC308)
  - Stewart, Samuel T. (CCNY Recorder's Office), 1937, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 16-1019, Box-folder 7-RC309)
  - Student Organizations: Broadsides, Handbills, Pamphlets, Interview Summaries (including Joseph P. Lash), 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0001, Box-folder 7-RC310)
  - Microfilm Error - This folder is not RC-311, but a partial repeat of previous folder (RC-310), 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0067, Box-folder 7-RC311)
  - Selsam, Millicent Ellis, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0077, Box-folder 7-RC312)
  - Social Frontier: Memo re: Charles J. Hendley's (President, Teachers Union) Remarks in May 1939 Issue, Oct 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0083, Box-folder 7-RC313)
  - Schappes, Morris U. (English, CCNY): News Articles, Flyers, Correspondence, Copy of Board of Higher Education Amended Change, Correspondence and Various Meeting Minutes (Teachers Union, CCNY Administrators Committee), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0088, Box-folder 7-RC314)
  - Selsam, Howard (Brooklyn College, Assistant Professor, Philosophy), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0252, Box-folder 7-RC315)
  - Microfilm Error - No Folder (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0306, Box-folder 7-RC316)
  - Smith Exhibits (Edward Smith, Assistant Director, Workers' School) in Response to Subpoena for all Personal, Student Records since 1935, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0307, Box-folder 7-RC317)
  - Squier, George C. (Government Department, Brooklyn College, ASU Advisor), 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0573, Box-folder 7-RC318)
  - Steinberg, Rose (Student, Brooklyn College), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0582, Box-folder 7-RC319)
  - Snyder, Elsa Rosenfeld (Teacher, Christopher Columbus High School), 1925-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0586, Box-folder 7-RC320)
  - Seward Park High School (Manhattan): Correspondence, Lists, Petitions, Flyers (much re: Robert P. Brodie, Principal), 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0684, Box-folder 7-RC321)
  - Sobel, Abraham, Jul 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0937, Box-folder 7-RC322)
  - Shaw, Robert (Physics), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0940, Box-folder 7-RC323)
  - Slochower, Harry (Brooklyn College, German): Correspondence, Articles, Interview Summary, Flyers, Memoranda, 1937-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0943, Box-folder 7-RC324)
  - Stuyvesant High School (Manhattan), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-0983, Box-folder 7-RC325)
  - Samuel Tilden High School (Brooklyn), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-1009, Box-folder 7-RC326)
  - Saveth, Edward N. (Instructor in History, CCNY), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-1055, Box-folder 7-RC327)
  - Selig, Kalman (Psychologist, CCNY), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 17-1063, Box-folder 7-RC328)
  - Schaul, Martin (Former CCNY Personnel Bureau Fellow), 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0001, Box-folder 7-RC329)
  - Skovron, Morris J. (Public School 4, Bronx; member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0013, Box-folder 7-RC330)
  - Smith, Harry B. (Brooklyn College, Psychology - Evening Session): Interviews, Correspondence, Aptitude Tests, Student Submissions (Class list subpoenaed because of alleged pro-left elements), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0017, Box-folder 7-RC331)
  - Smolar, Murray M. (CCNY Records Office), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0109, Box-folder 7-RC332)
  - Stein, Eugene (CCNY Recorder's Office), 1935, 1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0123, Box-folder 7-RC333)
  - Schlauch, Margaret (NYU, one of the editors of Science and Society): Publications including Science and Society and The Daily Worker; Correspondence, Flyers, Brochures, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0134, Box-folder 7-RC334)
  - Field and Sherritt Advanced Accounting (statement on textbook), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0253, Box-folder 7-RC335)
  - Thompson, Francis J. (Instructor in Public Speaking), 1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0258, Box-folder 7-RC336)
  - Thomas Jefferson High School, Brooklyn (handouts), (Samuel Levine, Principal): Correspondence, Reports, Flyers, Interviews, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0274, Box-folder 7-RC337)
  - Bulletins: Teachers Alliance of New York, Better Schools Publication, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0482, Box-folder 7-RC338)
  - Trachtenberg Exhibits: Regarding Book Contracts with Howard Selsam and with Harry Stochower (International Publishers, Alexander Trachtenberg, President), 1933-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0951, Box-folder 7-RC339)
  - Tremont Council for Peace and Civil Rights: Flyers, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0974, Box-folder 7-RC340)
  - Townsend Harris High School (re: American Student Union), 1937, 1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-0977, Box-folder 7-RC341)
  - United Parents Association,Inc.: Party Builder Publication, Correspondence, Interviews, Reports, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 18-1001, Box-folder 7-RC342)
  - Valenti, Frank, 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0001, Box-folder 7-RC343)
  - Voorhis Act ("Voorhis Blacklist Act") Regarding "Organizers under Foreign Control", 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0007, Box-folder 7-RC344)
  - Waivers (of Immunity) Used as Exhibits, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0030, Box-folder 7-RC345)
  - Washington Irving High School: Correspondence, Flyers and Information Sheet, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0052, Box-folder 7-RC346)
  - Werner, Bernard (CCNY, day student), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0065, Box-folder 7-RC347)
  - Weisberg, Herbert (CCNY Public Speaking Department), 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0068, Box-folder 7-RC348)
  - White, David McKelvy (formerly of Brooklyn College, Abraham Lincoln Brigade member), 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0076, Box-folder 7-RC349)
  - Wilcher Material (Amelia Wilcher - Art Teacher at Edward W. Stitt, Jr. High School #162, Harlem): Correspondence, Interview Summary, Flyers, Articles, Wilcher's Notebook - "Final Appeal to the Rapp-Coudert Committee", 1940-1942, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0099, Box-folder 8-RC350,1)
  - Wilcher Material, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0440, Box-folder 8-RC350,2)
  - Wolfe, B.D., undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0789, Box-folder 8-RC351)
  - Workers Alliance: Flyers, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0794, Box-folder 8-RC352)
  - Wisan, Joseph (CCNY, Assistant Professor, History), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0800, Box-folder 8-RC353)
  - Winter, Lester W. (Teacher, Townsend Harris High School), 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0804, Box-folder 8-RC354)
  - Wilson, George A. (CCNY, Music Department), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0826, Box-folder 8-RC355)
  - Wolfson, Hilliard (CCNY, Clerical Fellow), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0880, Box-folder 8-RC356)
  - Wolfson, Theresa (Brooklyn College), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0896, Box-folder 8-RC357)
  - Waldman, Mark (German Department, Brooklyn College), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0904, Box-folder 8-RC358)
  - Weiner, Philip Paul (Philosophy Department), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 19-0907, Box-folder 8-RC359)
  - Wardlaw, Ralph (Brooklyn College), 1935, 1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0001, Box-folder 8-RC360)
  - Warsoff, Louis (Brooklyn College, Department of Government), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0089, Box-folder 8-RC361)
  - Weisman, Maxwell (CCNY, Biology Department), 1941-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0097, Box-folder 8-RC362)
  - Wellnitz, Anna M. (Assistant Professor, Geology, Brooklyn College; Chair of Teachers' Alliance), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0113, Box-folder 8-RC363)
  - Weisner, Louis (Hunter College; member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0117, Box-folder 8-RC364)
  - Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1928, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0121, Box-folder 8-RC365)
  - Workers School: Includes List of Faculty Members Appearing as Members of the Teachers Union; also Items such as Testimony Summary, Executive Board minutes, and Course Catalog, 1933-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0132, Box-folder 8-RC366)
  - World Tourists, Inc. (175 5th Avenue; Jacob Rasin, President and General Manager), 1925-1939, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0204, Box-folder 8-RC367)
  - William Cullen Bryant High School (Long Island City, Queens; James P. Warren, Principal): Correspondence, Interview Memorandum, Publications including The Owl (student publication), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0404, Box-folder 8-RC368)
  - Yergen, Max (CCNY), 1936, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0493, Box-folder 8-RC369)
  - Zysman, Dale (Jack Hardy), (Public School 89, Manhattan, teacher dismissed by Board of Education December 11, 1942): Includes Hearing "Transcript - March 29, 1940" and Related Materials Such as Correpondence, Photographs, Publications and Testimony Summary, 1926-1942, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0499, Box-folder 8-RC370)
  - Bayevsky, Anna (WPA Teachers Union Job Representative, High School of Science), 1940-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0743, Box-folder 8-RC371)
  - W.P.A. Adult Education, 1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0822, Box-folder 8-RC372)
  - Young, Murray (Instructor, English Department, Brooklyn College), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0836, Box-folder 8-RC373)
  - Zeichner, Oscar, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 20-0846, Box-folder 8-RC374)
  - Young Communist League: Includes Photocopies of Newspapers, Periodicals, and Flyers, 1934-1943, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 21-0001, Box-folder 8-RC375)